0000,0000,0000,fx,学习
0000,0000,0000,fx,分享
0000,0000,0000,fx,进步
本字幕由ZiMuZu原创翻译
最新下载请登录www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译   草草  Reginamoon  王大可  charl
翻译   肉松  小憨加油  某羽
校对  油炸电风扇  杨一勾
时间轴  今 youliss 苏?love wins?菲
后期 斯人  总监 某羽
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    ustvboom
了解最新影视字幕发布信息
《诉讼双雄》前情提要
Previously on Suits...
监狱毁了克利福德的一生
Prison ruined Clifford's life.
如果你是我们的律师
And if you had been our lawyer,
他根本不会被判有罪
he never would have been convicted in the first place.
你想怎样
What do you want?
你坐两年牢
You do two years in prison,
我就放过你的朋友们
and I won't go after any of your friends.
这是唯一有把握的让事情归于平息方法
It's the only sure way to put this to bed
并能保证
and make sure that the only person
受损失的只有我一人
who is hurt by it is me.
那我呢
What about me?
我也只是爱你啊
All I did was love you.
我不会出卖他们的
I'm not gonna rat them out.
我不是劝你出卖他们
I'm not asking you to.
我只是希望你能对自己多点信心
I'm just asking you to have faith in yourself.
别再自愿承担后果了
Don't fall on your sword again.
我们可能赢不了
We might not win.
你不需要永远都做英雄
You don't always have to be the hero.
我那么做不是为了当英雄
I'm not doing it to be the hero.
那你为了什么
Then why the hell are you doing it?
我绝不会把朋友送进监狱的
I would never send my friends to prison.
如果他们给我定罪
They find me guilty,
也一样会送我朋友进监狱
they're gonna send my friends to prison anyways.
陪审团出来了  我们有一小时时间
The jury came back. We have an hour.
迈克呢
Where's Mike?
我不知道
I don't know.
我准备好接受协议了
I'm ready to take your deal.
哪个协议
Which one?
我们说清楚
So just to be clear,
你要的是这一份
this is the one you want to go with.
你入狱两年  你的朋友们不受指控
You go to prison for two years, your friends go free,
定下之后不得反悔
and no crying about it once it's done.
加一条
One stipulation.
我不会给你减刑的
I'm not reducing your jail time by one minute.
不是这个
That's not it.
我要你写清楚  我们签字后
I want you to write in that once we sign,
你不能再跟哈维重新定协议
you can't renegotiate with Harvey.
我知道了
Oh, I get it.
你是担心我会用这个
You're afraid I'm gonna use this
让他替你挡子弹
to get him to take the bullet for you.
我不是怕你会那么做
I'm not afraid of you trying to do that,
我知道你会那么做
because I know you will.
要么你写进去  要么我们等判决
So, either put it in, or we go to verdict.
记住  就像你对我说的
And just remember, like you said to me,
时间不多了
tick tock.
你做了什么
What did you do?
我必须做的
I did what I had to do.
我认罪了
I pled guilty.
胡扯
Bullshit.
你没认罪
You didn't plead anything.
哈维  看着我
Harvey, look at me.
是我犯了罪
It was my crime.
这是我的决定
It was my choice to make,
我做了决定
and I made it.
已经结束了
It's done.
我要推翻
Well, I'm gonna unmake it,
法官还没批准呢
because the judge hasn't ratified it yet,
在此之前  什么都没结束
and until she does, nothing is done.
哈维  停下
Harvey, stop.
不  你听我说
No, you listen to me.
如果你以为我会让你这么做
If you think I'm gonna let you do this,
你就是疯了
you're out of your goddamn mind.
做什么  迈克
Do what, Mike?
你做了什么
What did you do?
我接受了两年的协议
I took the two years.
-不  不会的  -瑞秋  求你
- No, no, you didn't. - Rachel, Rachel, please.
-我不接受  -听我说
- I don't accept that. - Please listen.
只有这样我才能...
It was the only way that I could--
不  不是只有这条路
No, it wasn't the only way.
你说你会等待判决的
You told me that you'd wait for the verdict,
我求你要相信自己
and I begged you to have faith in yourself,
你也说你会的
and you told me that you would.
那是在我求迪亚兹接受一个
That was before I begged Diaz to take a deal
出卖朋友的协议之前
that would rat out his friend,
他没听我说
and he didn't listen to me--
等等  你要放弃
Wait a second. You're throwing away
我们接下来的两年生活
the next two years of our lives
就因为个罪犯的话
for something that some criminal said?
-停下  听我说  -等等
- Just stop. Listen to me. - Hold on.
哈维说他不会允许这事发生
Harvey said he wasn't gonna let this happen.
他去见法官了  是吧
He went to see the judge, didn't he?
无所谓  他阻止不了
It doesn't matter. He can't stop it.
-为什么  -因为这事不在他
- Why not? - Because it's not up to him.
在我  我已经决定了
It's up to me, and I've made my decision.
瑞秋  你去哪
Rachel, where are you going?
哪儿都行
Anywhere else.
如果你要夺走
Because if you're gonna rob us
我们接下来两年的生活
of the next two years of our lives,
我不会站在这儿看着你那么做
I am not gonna stand here and watch you do it.
吉布斯女士  我不喜欢等人
Ms. Gibbs, I don't appreciate being kept waiting
尤其陪审团已经达成判决了
once the jury has informed us they've reached a verdict.
抱歉  法官大人
I'm sorry, your honor.
罗斯先生和我刚刚在完成一份认罪协议
Mr. Ross and I were finalizing a plea agreement.
我也抱歉  法官大人
I'm sorry too, your honor,
但他们狗屁都没完成
but they haven't finalized shit.
你刚刚在我的法庭上说了什么
What did you just say in my courtroom?
您没听错
You heard what I said.
立刻去我办公室
My chambers, right now.
瑞秋  我听说陪审团出来了
Rachel, I heard the jury is back.
我来听判决的
I came down to hear the verdict.
不会有判决了
There's not gonna be a verdict,
你掉头回去吧
so you can turn right around,
迈克认了罪  要去蹲两年监狱了
because Mike took a deal to spend two years in prison.
天呐
Oh, my god.
他们正在里面
And they're in there right now
签字呢
signing off on it.
我不知道该怎么办
And I don't know what to do.
好吧  我告诉你你该干什么
Okay, I'll tell you what you need to do.
你得回去
You need to go back inside,
陪在他身边
and you need to be there for him.
我才不要
I'm not gonna go back inside and be there for him.
为什么
Why not?
因为他告诉我他不会这么做
Because he told me that he wasn't going to do this.
他说有这个协议
He told me that it was on the table,
我求他不要接受
and I begged him not to take it,
他答应他不会的
and he promised me that he wouldn't.
瑞秋  哈维昨晚来找我
Rachel, last night Harvey came to me
也想这么做
wanting to do the same thing,
我求他要相信陪审团的
and I begged him to have faith in that jury.
哈维守了诺言
And Harvey kept his word.
但他也可能打破的
But he might not have,
我告诉自己  即便他改了主意
and I told myself that if he changed his mind,
我也必须原谅他
I would have to forgive him.
唐娜  你是个比我好的人
Then Donna, you're a better woman than I am,
因为迈克就是我的心
because Mike is my heart,
现在我感觉好像有人把我的心
and right now I feel like someone is ripping my heart
从胸膛里扯了出来  而那个人
out of my chest, and that someone--
就是他
that someone's him.
法官大人  我才不在乎那份协议
Your Honor, I don't give a shit about that deal.
她占了我的委托人的便宜
She took advantage of my client.
她强迫了他  您有权力阻止她
She coerced him, and you have the power to stop it.
我受够了你的粗口  斯佩克特先生
I've had enough of your language, Mr. Specter.
并非强迫
It wasn't coercion.
是一位有能力的律师商定的
It was negotiated by a competent attorney.
毫无问题  你也没有阻止它的依据
It's rock solid, and there's no basis to stop it.
他不是位有能力的律师
He's not a competent attorney.
他要承认诈骗罪签订协议呢
He's cutting a deal to plead guilty to fraud.
你想跟我签订另一种协议  我乐意听听
You want to cut a different deal with me? I'm all ears.
但问题是
Yeah, the only problem with that
你不能签别的协议了
is you can't sign a different deal,
因为你已经签字放弃这一权利了
because you already signed your rights to that away.
该死的  迈克  别这么做
God damn it, Mike, don't do this.
我们可以等判决
We can go to verdict.
别跟我来那套
Don't give me that.
你冲去她的办公室
You weren't racing over to her office
不是为了告诉她陪审团回来了
to tell her that the jury was back.
你是想跳过去盖住手雷
You were going to jump on the grenade,
而我先你一步
and I beat you to it.
我说了  结束了  已经结束了
Now I told you it's done, and it's done.
你十分确定吗  罗斯先生
Are you absolutely sure, Mr. Ross?
是的  法官大人
I am, Your Honor.
那么  罗斯先生  给你72小时
Then, Mr. Ross, you have 72 hours
去丹伯里联邦监狱报到
to report to Danbury Federal Prison.
直接告诉我结果
Give it to me straight.
什么情况
What happened?
迈克认罪了  作为交换
Mike pled guilty, and in exchange,
他们不能再动你  哈维  路易  我们任何人
they can't go after you, Harvey, Louis, or any of us.
该死
Shit.
作为刚刚得知
For someone who just found out
自己不会进监狱的人来说  你怎么不高兴呢
she's not going to prison, you don't seem happy.
我担心的从来不是进监狱  唐娜
I was never worried about going to prison, Donna.
那你担心什么
What are you worried about?
失去我的公司
Losing my firm.
迈克认了罪  他经手过的每一桩案子
Now that Mike pled guilty, every case he ever touched
都将变成"官司"
has "lawsuit" written all over it.
那我们要怎么办
So what are we gonna do?
我告诉你我们要怎么办
I'll tell you what we're going to do.
我们要重组这家律所
We're gonna restructure this firm,
而且我们得在官司打起来前就重组
and we're gonna do it before the lawsuits even start.
把路易叫来
Get me Louis.
迈克
Michael.
格洛丽亚  你在这里干什么
Gloria, what are you doing here?
我过来陪你听判决的
I came here to be with you for the verdict,
但他们告诉我你达成了协议
but they told me you made a deal.
的确
I did.
迈克  主怎么能让我看着两个
Michael, there's no way the lord would have
无辜的人去坐牢啊
put me through two innocent men going away.
但是丹纳女士  我并不无辜
But Mrs. Danner, I'm not innocent,
我确实做了他们所控诉我的那些事
and I did what they accused me of.
我又不傻  迈克
I'm not stupid, Michael.
我不是指你上过法学院
I didn't mean you went to law school.
我指的是你的内心是清白的
I meant you are innocent in your heart,
而如今你却选择去一个
and now you've chosen to go to a place
满是内心不清白的人的地方
filled with men who aren't.
我想您是没搞清楚
I don't think you understand.
我要去的是一个白领监狱
I'm going to a white-collar prison.
一旦大门一关  可就没什么
There's no such thing as a white-collar prison
白领监狱一说了
once they close those doors.
你得听我的
You need to hear me.
格洛丽亚  听着  我知道你是想帮我
Gloria, look, I know that you are trying to help,
但我是为了自己的所为承担责任
but I took responsibility for what I did,
我将要忍受这一点
and I'm gonna live with it.
但如今  我得去和我爱的女人待在一起
But right now, I need to go spend time with the woman I love
并且把事情处理好
and make things right,
所以很抱歉  容我先行一步
so I'm sorry, but you have to excuse me.
罗伯特  我收到你的信息了
Robert, I got your message.
然后马上赶了过来
I rushed right over.
瑞秋怎么了
What happened to Rachel?
我告诉你她怎么了
I'll tell you what happened.
迈克・罗斯要进监狱了
Mike Ross is going to jail,
我的女儿心都碎了
my daughter is heartbroken,
但哈维和杰西卡却毫发无伤地脱罪了
and Harvey and Jessica are getting off scot-free.
等等  假如你把我引下来
Wait a second. If you lured me down here
只是因为想找个出气筒
because you wanted a punching bag,
我可以告诉你  那种事不可能发生
I can tell you right now, that's not gonna happen.
我来告诉你会发生什么
Well, let me tell you what is gonna happen.
马上  迈克用他那毫无意义的名声所
It's about to be open season on every case
担保的每一桩案子  都要开始重审了
that Mike Ross ever put his good-for-nothing name on,
一旦开始了
and once that happens,
或早或晚
it's just a matter of time
你手下每一个律师都会试图跳槽了
until every one of your attorneys tries to leave.
我明白这是怎么回事了
I see what this is.
你想利用我来引发一场
You want to use me to start an avalanche
会活埋了哈维和杰西卡的雪崩
that will bury Harvey and Jessica.
你猜怎么着
Guess what?
我不会干这种事的
I'm not gonna do it.
那你就是比我想象中还要蠢了
Then you're a bigger fool than I thought,
因为我会找到一个愿意做的人
because I'm gonna find someone that will.
祝你好运  因为我们有非竞争条款
Good luck with that, because we have a noncompete.
不是人人都有  你就没有
Not anymore, you don't.
放屁  你是在虚张声势
Bullshit. You're bluffing.
你何不去问问你的前助理卡特里娜
Then why don't you go and ask your ex-associate Katrina?
因为一开始就是她给我提供的
Because she's the one that gave me
这个规避规则的办法
the way around it in the first place.
哈维  我听说了迈克的事了
Harvey, I heard about Mike.
真是太可惜了
I am so sorry.
别可惜了
Well, you can stop being sorry
给我搞到那个陪审团主席的名字
and get me the name of that jury foreman.
哈维  你申请不到无效审判的
Harvey, you can't get a mistrial.
已经太迟了  迈克已经达成协议了
It's too late. Mike cut a deal.
我不需要法律建议  唐娜
I don't need legal advice, Donna.
我只需要那个主席的姓名和住址
I need the name and address of that foreman.
我不认为那是个好主意
I don't think that's a good idea.
又不是要犯法  唐娜
It's not breaking the law anymore, Donna.
只是叫你帮个忙
It's just a favor.
我又不会毁了他的生活
I'm not gonna ruin his life.
我只需要问他一个该死的问题
I just need to ask him a goddamn question.
在你告诉我那个问题是什么之前
Well, I'm not gonna do that until you tell me
我是不会帮你的
what that question is.
唐娜...
Donna...
迈克刚刚抛弃了自己的整个人生
Mike just threw his whole life away,
而我却对此无能为力
and there's nothing I can do about it,
唯一能让我接受这一点的方式
and the only way that I can accept it
就是我去问清楚原本的判决是什么
is if I find out what that verdict was gonna be.
我帮你去搞到名字
I'll get you the name.
罗伯特・赞恩刚刚告诉我
Robert Zane just told me
他能解除我们的非竞争条款
he can take away our noncompete.
我要你立马告诉我他要如何做到这一点
I need you to tell me right now how he's gonna do that.
很高兴见到你  路易
Nice to see you too, Louis.
我能给你来杯李子泥吗
Can I offer you a prunie?
不  我不要什么该死的李子泥
No, I don't need a damn prunie.
我需要你告诉我他在打什么主意
I need you to tell me what he's up to.
路易  我如今人在这里
Louis, I'm here now,
而我之所以在这里
and the reason I'm here
是因为我因帮你而被开除了
is that I got fired for helping you,
而且即便你保证过在你成为冠名合伙人后
and even though you promised to bring me back
就让我回去
once you were named partner,
但你失约了
you didn't.
不不不不不
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
我想让你回来  卡特里娜  非常想
I wanted to bring you back, Katrina, more than anything.
别和我来这一套  路易
Don't give me that, Louis.
在希拉甩了你之后我为你打掩护
I covered for you after Sheila dumped you.
我帮你挖到了回春制药
I helped you poach Versalife.
我甚至帮你伪造了政府文件
I even forged government documents for you.
好吧  卡特里娜  我想要让你回来
Okay, Katrina, I wanted to bring you back,
但我没办法保护你不受...
I couldn't protect you--
不受什么
From what?
不受发现迈克・罗斯是骗子这个真相的伤害吗
From finding out Mike Ross is a fraud?
没错  我算过了  路易
Yeah, I did the math, Louis,
你没办法保护我不受这件事的伤害
and you couldn't have protected me from it,
却可以利用这点让自己当上冠名合伙人
but you could use it to get your name on the door,
是不是
couldn't you?
你要看着我的眼睛告诉我事实并非如此吗
Are you gonna look me in the eye and tell me that isn't true?
事实就是如此
It's true.
我感激你的坦诚
Well, I appreciate your honesty.
既然你对我坦诚  我也会对你坦诚
Since you were honest with me, I'll be honest with you.
我帮不了你
I can't help you.
你还好吧
Are you okay?
不好
No.
瑞秋...
Rachel...
我就不明白了  迈克
I just don't understand, Mike.
你告诉过我你会等判决出来的
You told me you'd wait for the verdict.
我知道
I know.
瑞秋  听我说  好吗
Rachel, listen to me, all right?
我这么做不是想伤害你
I didn't do this to hurt you.
我这么做是因为我本性如此
I did it because it's who I am.
我明白
I know that.
那你为什么还要怪我呢
Then why are you holding it against me?
因为一想到要失去你我就无法忍受
Because I can't stand the thought of losing you.
你不会失去我的
You're not gonna lose me.
不  我会的  迈克  要失去两年
Yes, I am, Mike, for two years.
本来可能是七年呢
And it could have been seven.
-也可能是无罪  -他们...
- It could have been zero. - They took--
你为什么就不能等到判决出来呢
Why couldn't you just wait for the verdict?
因为我只求下半辈子
Because I have to live with myself
过得心安理得
for the rest of my life.
我做出了决定  而我...
I made a decision, and I...
我没办法回到过去改变主意了
I can't go back in time and change it.
但如今我们在这里呢
But we are here right now, all right?
我们还有三天时间
We have--we have three days left.
我得抽出一天独自待着
I'm gonna have to take one of those days for myself...
因为你向我保证过你会对自己有信心的
because you promised me that you would have faith in yourself.
但你失约了
And you didn't.
记得我吗
You remember me?
怎么可能不记得
How could I not?
我听你说话听了快两周的时间
I listened to you for the better part of two weeks.
那我就直说了
Then I'll get right to it.
我需要你帮我个忙
I need a favor.
你有卡车要修吗
You got a truck needs fixing?
我想知道最终的判决是什么
I want to know what that verdict was gonna be.
你不想
No, you don't.
是的  我想
Yeah, I do.
知道了又有什么不同呢
What difference does it make?
那将大有不同
It makes all the difference in the world.
那我就告诉你
Then I'll tell you,
因为我非常想告诉别人
'cause I've been dying to tell somebody,
因为我们就像《十二怒汉》一样
'cause it was "12 angry men" in there,
而我就是那一个异类
And I was the one.
是的
Yeah, that's right.
我一个又一个的将他们争取过来
One by one, I put that jury on my back
然后做了正确的决定
and we did the right thing.
什么是正确的决定
What's the right thing?
你以为我不知道真相吗
You think I don't know what's what?
那个孩子并没有读过法学院
That kid didn't go to law school.
你知  我知
You know it, I know it,
那个屋子里的所有人都知道
everybody in the goddamn room knew it.
是有罪
It was guilty.
我没那么说
I didn't say that.
那个女人的案子站不住脚
That woman didn't make her case,
我也不会让我的国家的司法体制
and I'm not letting my country's justice system
在我的手上沾上污点
go to shit on my watch.
说吧
Say it.
无罪
Not guilty.
他们说你们达成了某种协议
They told us you guys cut some kind of deal.
你们应该对体制多点信心的
Guess you should have had a little more faith in the system.
斯佩克特先生
Mr. Specter?
Mr. Specter.
丹纳女士  您有什么事
Mrs. Danner, what can I do for you?
我试图说服迈克  但他不听
I tried to talk to Michael, but he wouldn't listen.
说服他什么
Talk to him about what?
告诉他监狱里面是什么样子
About what's gonna happen to him inside that prison.
丹纳女士  我很感激你到这里来
Mrs. Danner, I appreciate you coming down here,
但我现在不能和你聊这些
but I can't talk about this right now.
我不在乎
I don't care.
你必须听我说
You're gonna listen to what I have to say,
我知道监狱对我儿子的影响  斯佩克特先生
because I saw what prison did to my son, Mr. Specter.
迈克需要知道
Michael needs to know
进去之后的第一天是什么样子
what his first day is gonna be like,
应该和什么样的人交朋友
who to make friends with,
要远离哪些警卫
what guards to stay away from,
因为警卫才是最可怕的
because it's the guards that are the worst.
你以为我不知道吗
You think I don't know all that?
那就做些什么帮帮那个孩子
Then do something to toughen up that boy.
我说了  我现在不能谈这些
I told you, I can't talk about this right now.
随你便
Go ahead.
走吧
Walk away.
但你欠我的
But you owe me.
因为也许你能把他救出来
Because you may have gotten him out,
但是也正是因为你
but you're also the one who put him in that hellhole
他才会进去
in the first place.
路易  你到底去哪了
Louis, where the hell have you been?
-我们有麻烦了  -你以为我不知道
- We have a problem. - You think I don't know that?
我需要你把律所分割
I need you to bifurcate the firm
成两个实体  我需要你现在就去弄
into two entities, and I need you to do it now.
我知道你的想法
I know what you're thinking.
如果我们把客户隔离  我们就可以留住律师
If we insulate our clients, we can hold on to our lawyers,
但那并没有什么用
but that won't help.
为什么没用
Why the hell not?
因为罗伯特・赞恩已经找到方法破除
Because Robert Zane has a way to
我们的非竞争条款了
bust our noncompete.
该死的
God damn it.
他找到一个愿意去的人
He finds somebody to jump ship,
那就会有一帮人蜂拥去投奔他
it'll be a stampede for the exits.
这正是我想说的
That's what I'm trying to tell you.
好吧  那就不用分割律所了
All right, then forget about splitting the firm
去查一下他想挖谁
and work on figuring out what the hell he's up to,
不然我们根本不会剩下什么律所了
or there won't be a firm left to split.
我需要和你谈谈
I need to talk to you.
不行  迈克  现在不行
I can't, Mike, not now.
哈维  我需要知道你是否认为
Harvey, I need to know if you think
认罪是正确的决定
I did the right thing taking that plea.
该死的  你现在来问我了
God damn it, you ask me that now?
瑞秋无法接受
Rachel can't get past the fact
我没有等到判决就做决定
that I didn't wait for the verdict to come in.
她非常伤心  我也因此而心痛
It's tearing her up, and that's tearing me up.
-迈克  -哈维  我知道你很生气
- Mike-- - Harvey, I know that you are pissed
我在你之前就达成了协议
that I made a deal before you,
但是我需要你告诉我我的决定是正确的
but I need you to tell me that I made the right call.
你做得对
You did.
你怎么知道
How can you be sure?
因为我去找过陪审团主席
Because I went to see the foreman,
他告诉我他们的判决是有罪
and he told me the verdict was guilty.
什么
What?
听着  你进监狱这件事也让我非常难过
Look, the idea of you going to prison was killing me,
如果我不知道结果会一直纠结
and I couldn't let it go unless I knew.
但你现在不用了
But now you can.
我仍然希望你能让我替你承受这一切
I still wish you would have let me take the hit instead of you,
是的  现在不纠结了
But yeah, I can.
回家吧  迈克
Go home, Mike.
用你所剩的时间去陪瑞秋吧
Get whatever time left you have with Rachel.
现在轻松多了
It's gonna be easier now.
从没想过"有罪"两个字还能有这种效果
I never thought the word "Guilty" would do that.
你还好吗
Are you all right?
我没事
I'm fine.
我能帮你做些什么吗
Can I get you anything?
是的
Yeah.
清空你今天的所有安排
Clear your schedule for the rest of the day.
我需要你帮我搜集迈克庭审的所有资料
I need you to get me everything there is to get from Mike's trial.
哈维  我不明白
Harvey, I don't understand.
你说如果你和那个陪审团主席聊过
You said if you talked to that foreman,
你就能放下这件事了
you would be able to make peace with this.
我不在乎我说了什么
I don't care what I said.
但他说了迈克有罪
And he said that Mike was guilty,
迈克也接受了这种结果
and Mike accepted those consequences.
他没说迈克有罪
He didn't say Mike was guilty.
他说他是无辜的
He said he was goddamn innocent.
我的天哪
Oh, my god.
他要白白承受牢狱之灾了
He's going away for nothing.
不  唐娜  他根本不会去坐牢
No, Donna, he's not going away at all.
你需要我做什么
What do you need me to do?
我需要你帮我
I need you to get me
整理案件的全部信息
everything we have on that trial,
因为我要找到方法
because I'm gonna figure out a way
让那个协议无效
to invalidate that goddamn deal.
杰西卡  你有时间吗
Jessica, do you have a minute?
我现在真的很忙  杰克
I'm really busy right now, Jack.
恐怕这件事不能等
I'm afraid this can't wait.
我正式向你提出辞呈
I'm officially giving you my letter of resignation.
我猜猜
Let me guess.
罗伯特・赞恩向你发出了邀请
Robert Zane made you an offer.
是的
He did,
尽管我非常不想接受
and as much as I didn't want to take it,
但我不得不
I have to.
不得不
Oh, you have to?
你求我再给你一次机会
You begged me for a second chance
然后又是第三次  第四次机会
and a third and a fourth,
我每次都答应了
and I gave them all to you,
现在他是要利用你摧毁我们
and now he's using you to destroy us.
我们已经被摧毁了
We're already destroyed.
你只是不想接受现实
You just don't want to accept it.
不  这只是个挫折
No, this is a setback.
对不起
I'm sorry.
杰克
Jack.
我觉得你忘记了你给过我一个文件夹
I think you're forgetting about that folder you gave me,
那个证明你有些许法律问题的文件夹
the one with the little legal indiscretion
被丹尼尔・哈德曼抓住的
Daniel Hardman had on you.
不要说得那么委婉  杰西卡
Let's not soft-pedal it, Jessica.
那不是不检点  那直接就是犯罪
It wasn't an indiscretion. It was a flat-out crime.
如果把它公之于众
And the problem with you using it is,
就相当于告诉全世界
you'll be announcing to the world
你眼皮底下发生了另一桩犯罪
yet another crime happened under your watch,
而你却没有阻止
and you did nothing to stop it.
而之前愿意留下的客户
And whatever clients were willing to stay with you before
也不会愿意了
won't be willing to anymore.
我想我最想念的会是这个
I think I'm gonna miss this the most.
想念什么
Miss what?
回家见到你
Coming home to you.
瑞秋  我知道我在签协议之前
Rachel, I know I should have told you what I was gonna do
应该告诉你
before I made that deal,
但我之前也不知道我会那样做
but I didn't know I was gonna do it,
我只有  三秒左右的时间做决定
and I had, like, three seconds to make a decision.
而那三秒拿走了整整两年
And those three seconds took away two whole years.
其实  是还给了我们五年
Actually, gave us back five.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
哈维找到了陪审团主席
Harvey found the jury foreman.
他们本来要判我有罪
They were gonna find me guilty.
我们只有三天时间  我却浪费了一天
And we only had three days, and I took away one of them.
没关系的
Hey, it's okay.
瑞秋  我不在乎
Rachel, I don't care.
只要我们没事就好
As long as we're good.
我不要我们只是没事而已
I don't want us to just be good.
我要我们在一起
I want us to be one.
我想在你走之前成为你的妻子
I want to be your wife before you go.
我想成为你的丈夫
I want to be your husband.
我给我们弄了些咖啡
Okay, I got us some coffees and--
唐娜  搞什么  这不是所有的东西
Donna, what the hell? This isn't everything.
什么叫这不是所有的东西
What do you mean, this isn't everything?
我是说  她得提交动议
I mean, she had to have filed motions
申请传票  然后搜查
and subpoenas and discovery,
而这些东西什么都不是
And all this shit is nothing.
-哈维  这几箱是  -什么
- Harvey, these boxes are-- - what?
这是没有他在上面的班级排名
This is his class ranking that he wasn't on.
这是他的成绩单
This is his transcript.
这是他的年鉴
This is his yearbook.
我们可以在程序上反击的东西在哪里
Where are the things that we can attack procedurally?
在那边
They're over there.
那你为什么还没理清楚那些
Then why haven't you gone through them?
因为那不是我要做的
Because that's not what I do.
那你在这里到底是在干什么
Then what in god's name are you doing in here?
我在支持你  哈维  而现在
I'm supporting you, Harvey, and right now,
我要给你点空间
I'm gonna do that by giving you some space.
如果你以为你可以大摇大摆的
If you think you can waltz into my firm
走进我的公司  挖走我的律师
and take my lawyers,
你一定是疯了
you must be out of your damn mind.
让我猜猜  你要告我引诱
Let me guess, you're suing me for inducement.
那是当然
You bet your ass I am.
你引诱杰克・索罗夫违反他的竞业限制
You induced Jack Soloff into breaking his noncompete.
你对杰克・索罗夫或者其他人都没有竞业限制
You don't have a noncompete with jack soloff or anyone else.
我听说你用这句空话吓了路易
I heard you tried that empty threat with Louis,
但这招对我没用
but it's not gonna work with me.
如果这是空话
If it is empty,
那你的道德条款和章程也都是空话
then so is your morals clause and your bylaws,
因为里面说如果有冠名合伙人
which states that if a named partner
参与犯罪活动  所有合伙人都可以离开
participates in a crime, any partner is free to go.
而谋划诈骗就是该死的犯罪
And conspiracy to commit fraud is a goddamn crime.
你无法证明我们之前知道迈克・罗斯的事
You can't prove we knew about Mike Ross.
让我提醒你  你问了路易・利特
Well, let me suggest that you ask Louis Litt
他今天早上跟卡特里娜・班尼特的对话
about his conversation with Katrina Bennett this morning.
我抓到你的把柄了  杰西卡
I got you, Jessica,
如果你因为我雇了杰克
And if you want to come after me
或者其他任何人  来对付我
for hiring jack, or anyone for hiring anyone,
你可能不用进监狱
You may not go to jail,
但是全世界都会知道你的所作所为
but the world is gonna know what you did.
你为什么要这么做  罗伯特
Why are you doing this, Robert?
我根本不在乎你雇了个骗子  杰西卡
I don't give a shit about you hiring a fraud, Jessica,
但他开始和瑞秋交往的时候
but you never came to me with it
你没来告诉我
once he started dating rachel.
我怎么知道我可以信任你
How could I have known I could have trusted you
不会来对付我的公司
not to come after my firm?
罗伯特桌上的那张照片
That picture on robert's desk
就可以让你知道  杰西卡
is how you could have known, Jessica.
如果你不介意的话  我们该去剧院了
Now if you'll excuse us, we have tickets for the theater.
刚才不好意思  唐娜
Sorry about before, Donna.
没关系  哈维  我能理解
It's okay, Harvey. I understand.
我在想我们处理这件事的方式不对
And I've been thinking we're going about this all wrong.
你是什么意思
What do you mean?
用法律细节上诉
I mean appealing something based on legal minutiae
不是你该做的
isn't what you do.
那我该做什么
And what exactly is it that I do?
你用其他东西
You get people to do things they don't want to
来让别人去做他门本来不想做的事
by giving them something else.
唐娜  我不能那样对付吉布斯
Donna, I can't do that with Gibbs,
因为她真正想抓的是我
because what she really wants is me,
而迈克不会让我这么做的
and Mike won't let me.
那如果你给她更大的东西呢
And what if you give her something bigger?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我是说自由铁路公司
I'm talking about Liberty Rail.
不行
No.
哈维  如果我们愿意让我为自己做的事
Harvey, if we're willing to let me be prosecuted
被审判  那你就可以带给吉布斯
for what I did, then you can give Gibbs
犯了谋杀罪的人并且让迈克幸免于难
people who committed murder and get Mike off the hook.
二比一
Two for one.
唐娜  我不会拿你去换迈克的
Donna, I am not trading you for Mike.
就这样
Period.
那我们怎么办
Then what are we gonna do?
我们要把谋杀犯交给吉布斯
We're gonna give Gibbs her murderers
但不让你受伤害
without giving you up at all.
路易  告诉我
Louis, tell me right now.
你向卡特里娜・班尼特承认
Did you admit to Katrina Bennett
你知道迈克・罗斯的事了吗
that you knew about Mike Ross?
道德条款
The morals clause.
该死的
God damn it.
杰西卡  她早就知道了
Jessica, she already knew.
她知道跟你直接承认
Her knowing and you flat-out confessing
不是一回事
aren't the same thing.
无所谓  她证明不了
It doesn't matter. She can't prove it.
路易  你还不明白吗
Louis, don't you get it?
卡特里娜・班尼特可是你教出来的
Katrina Bennett was your protégé.
你所有见不得人的小动作
All that underhanded shit that you do,
她都学会了
she learned all of it.
你在说什么
What are you saying?
我是说她录音了
I'm saying that she recorded you,
如果那个录音被公之于众的话
and if that tape ever sees the light of day,
所有合伙人只要想走
any partner who wants can walk out that door
就可以带着他们的客户走出那扇门
and take their clients with them.
不  他们走不了
No, they can't.
你去哪里
Where are you going?
档案室
To the file room.
你说得对  杰西卡
You're right, Jessica.
卡特里娜是我教出来的
Katrina was my protégé,
她知道我所有见不得人的事
and she knows all my dirty laundry,
但我也知道她的
but I also know hers.
我来付吧
Let me take care of it.
不用
I don't think so.
上次我们不欢而散
After the way we ended things last time,
至少可以替你买个单
it's the least I can do.
你想怎么样  哈维
What do you want, Harvey?
我想要自由铁路公司
I want Liberty Rail.
那是不可能的
Well, that's never gonna happen,
你需要放下这件事了
and you need to let that shit go.
我需要的是用这件事换迈克・罗斯的自由
What I need is to trade that shit for Mike Ross's freedom.
你在说什么
What the hell are you talking about?
你把自由铁路公司给我
You give me Liberty Rail,
我会给你五个我最好的客户
I'll give you five of my best clients.
杰西卡・皮尔逊不会同意的
There's no way Jessica Pearson allows that to happen.
她说了不算
It's not her call.
他们是我的客户
They're my clients.
我不在乎
Well, I don't care,
因为我不会为了五个客户
because I'm not breaking privilege
违反保密协议还冒着丢饭碗的危险
and risking my entire career in exchange for five clients.
你想怎么样
What's it gonna take?
你想让我开价
You want my price?
我想去皮尔逊-斯佩克特-利特律所采购一番
I want to go shopping at Pearson Specter Litt.
有权雇我想雇的任何人
Exclusive access to hire anyone I want,
从律师助理到高级合伙人以及他们的客户
from paralegals to senior partners and their clients,
整整下个月
for the next month.
你会毁掉律所
You'd be gutting the firm.
你觉得我在乎吗
Do I look like I care?
杰西卡不可能同意
There is no way Jessica accepts this,
你也清楚
and you know it.
我只清楚  人们太渴望时
What I know is, people will do anything
就愿意做任何事
if they're desperate enough.
而如果你来找我了
And if you're in here doing this,
那说明你太渴望救迈克・罗斯
then you're desperate to save Mike Ross.
迈克尔  如果你来见罗伯特
Michael, if you're here to see Robert,
他已经出门了
he's already gone.
我不是来见罗伯特的
I'm not here to see Robert.
我是来见你的
I'm here to see you.
那我希望你走
Well, I'd rather you go.
劳拉  拜托
Laura, please.
拜托什么  迈克尔
Please what, Michael?
罗伯特和我已经准备好接受
Robert and I were ready to embrace
要娶我们女儿的男人
the man who was going to marry our daughter,
结果那人是个骗子
and it turns out, that man is a liar.
你还想让我说服我丈夫
And now you're here to get me to convince my husband
去你的婚礼吗
to go to your wedding?
不只是我的婚礼
It's not just my wedding.
也是瑞秋的
It's also Rachel's.
我可以跟罗伯特谈到面色发青
And I can talk to Robert until I'm blue in the face.
但他绝不会原谅你
He will never forgive you.
他不必原谅我  好吗
He doesn't need to forgive me, all right?
他只用支持他的女儿
He just needs to be there for his daughter.
-他不会那么做的  -为什么
- He's not gonna do that. - Why not?
因为你毁了她的人生
Because you're ruining her life.
劳拉  我知道我犯了大错
Look, Laura, I know that I made a horrible mistake.
为此我要坐两年牢
I'm going away for two years,
而我本可以靠背叛朋友脱罪的
when I could have gotten out of it by turning in my friends.
瑞秋懂我是什么人
Rachel knows that's the kind of man that I am.
所以她才想和我共度此生
That's why she wants to spend the rest of her life with me.
而现在  我只求你让罗伯特看到这一点
Now all-all I am asking you is that you help Robert see that.
我了解我丈夫
I know my husband.
你的要求不可能
What you're asking is impossible,
我也不指望你明白
and I don't expect you to understand that,
因为你从没当过女儿的父亲
because you've never been the father of a daughter.
但我会尽力的
But I'll try.
我不懂
I don't understand.
你当然不懂
Of course you don't,
因为你也从没当过女儿的母亲
because you've also never been the mother of a daughter.
路易
Louis.
你来干什么
What are you doing here?
你为什么那么做
Why'd you do it?
做什么
Do what?
别给我装傻  卡特里娜
Don't be coy with me, Katrina.
分享律所章程是一回事
It's one thing to share our bylaws,
但我知道你录了我的音  我想知道原因
but I know you recorded me, and I want to know why.
因为我想让罗伯特・赞恩注意我
I did it because it put my name on the map with Robert Zane.
如果你不毁掉录音
If you don't destroy that recording,
我就让你被别人注意
it's gonna put your name on the map somewhere else.
这是你之前让我伪造的文件的复印件
This is a copy of the document I forged for you.
没错  你昨天提醒我的那份
Yeah, the one you reminded me of yesterday,
如果你不放手  我也会把这份
the same one that I'm gonna give to the SEC
交给证监会
if you don't back off.
你不必这么做
You don't have to do this.
你还可以来与我们同事
You can still come work with us.
不  我做不到  就像我想
No, I can't, and even if I wanted to,
我也不再相信你了
I can't trust you anymore.
这不公平
That's not fair.
如果不找我  你也会找别人
If it wasn't me, it would've been somebody else.
但的确是你  卡特里娜
But it was you, Katrina.
我自己的门徒背后捅我一刀
My own protégé stabbing me in the back?
我只想让自己小有名气
I was just trying to make a name for myself.
我还只是当上冠名合伙人呢
And I just wanted my name on the wall,
但我告诉你
but let me tell you something.
如果我学到了教训
If there's one thing that I have learned,
那就是完全不值得为了出名
it's not worth being willing to do anything
而不择手段
to make a name for yourself.
杰西卡  我得跟你谈谈
Jessica, I need to talk to you.
哈维  我在你提问之前告诉你
Harvey, before you ask whatever you're about to ask,
我没心情
I'm not in the mood.
那也阻止不了我
Well, that's not gonna cut it.
你得放弃伊凡・施密斯的不竞争条款
I need you to waive our noncompetes for Evan Smith.
开玩笑吗
Is this a joke?
这是让迈克不进监狱的唯一办法
It's the only way to keep Mike out of prison.
没办法让迈克不进监狱
There is no way to keep Mike out of prison.
不  有办法
Yes, there is.
把已经想走的人给伊凡
We give Evan people who already want to go,
我给安妮塔・吉布斯凶手名单交换迈克
and I give Anita Gibbs murderers in exchange for Mike.
我过去二十四小时
And I've just spent the last 24 hours
都在设法保住不竞争条款
fighting to keep our noncompetes.
-杰西卡  -不
- Jessica. - No.
他为了救律所达成协议
He cut a deal to save this firm.
他为了不让我们进监狱达成协议
He cut a deal to keep us from going to prison,
你心里清楚
and you know it.
要知道  我根本不关心
You know, I don't give a shit
他达成协议时的想法
what he thought when he made that deal.
他本来会判无罪
He was gonna be found innocent.
什么
What?
我去见了陪审团主席
I went to see the foreman.
判决本来是无罪
The verdict was gonna be not guilty.
那告诉我你和吉布斯的协议
Then let me see your deal with Gibbs.
我还没拿到
I don't have it yet.
你疯了吗
Are you crazy?
你让我为了协议对律所进行大屠杀
You're asking me to decimate my firm
而你根本不清楚她接不接受
for a deal you don't even know she'll take?
-我会让她接受的  -你保证不了
- I’ll make her take the deal. - You don't know that.
我可以
Yes, I do.
杰西卡  我们有机会救迈克
Jessica, we have a chance to save Mike
让那些想走的人走
and let the people who want to go, go.
但如果我们输了一切还不管用呢
And what if it doesn't work and we lose everything?
那就这样了
Then we do.
杰西卡  哈维说得没错
Jessica, Harvey's right.
迈克是家人
Mike's family.
就算我们失去了半个律所  但如果没尽力救他
Even if we lose half the firm, if we don't try to save him,
那我们是怎样的人
who are we?
达成协议
Make the deal.
-爸  -他人呢
- Da.. - Where is he?
他不在家
He's not here.
那太糟了
Well, that's too bad
因为我来跟他谈
because I came here to talk to him,
尽管他根本没胆跟我谈
even though he didn't have the balls to talk to me.
他有胆跟你谈
He wasn't afraid to talk to you.
他去找妈妈了  因为我让他这么做
He went to mom because I asked him to.
好吧
Oh, okay.
好吧  话说清楚了
Okay, let's down to this.
你嫁给他  他就会毁掉你的人生
You marry him, and that man ruins your life.
怎么会呢  爸
How, dad?
我们会挺过接下来两年  然后
We're gonna get through the next two years and then--
然后怎样
And then what?
因为你肯定做不成律师了
Because you're sure as shit not gonna be a lawyer.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我在说你的毕业问题
I'm talking about you graduating,
你还要去面对
and then you're gonna stand before
律师性格健康委员会
the character and fitness committee of the bar.
据我所知
And the last time I checked,
嫁给一个欺骗过他们的男人
marrying a man that defrauded them
是不会让你进入律师协会的
isn't gonna get you in.
好吧  但是等到那时
Okay, and by the time that happens,
他已经服完刑  我们就已经偿清了他的罪过
he will have served his time, and we will have paid his debt.
那样做到底有什么不同呢
What the hell difference does that make?
不同之处在于
The difference is
那样做关乎我们司法系统的一切
that's what our justice system is all about,
而且永远支持你所爱的人
and standing behind the man that you love
正是性格健康的含义
is the definition of character and fitness.
很好  你对他们说这话
Okay, you tell them that,
他们会告诉你和你的重刑犯丈夫
and they're gonna tell you and your felon husband
-去见鬼吧  -那不会发生的
- to go to hell. - That's not gonna happen.
就是会发生  该死的
Oh, yes it is, god damn it!
这些都是复仇心切  保护欲强的人
These are vindictive and protective people,
而他又把他们当成傻子
and he make them look like fools.
此事并不关于我不能做律师
This isn't about me not becoming a lawyer
也不是关于他毁了我的生活
or him ruining my life
更不是关于你在此说的其他废话
or any of this other bullshit that you're in here saying.
而是因为他欺骗了你
This is because he pulled one over on you.
不能信任他
He can't be trusted!
爸爸  很抱歉我对你隐瞒了此事
Dad, I'm sorry that I kept this from you,
但是他并没对我隐瞒
but he didn't keep it from me,
而且我告诉你我能信任他
and I'm telling you I can trust him.
那我如何信任你呢
And how can I trust you?
如果你不信任我
Well, if you can't,
那或许你就不应该去参加婚礼
then maybe you shouldn't come to the wedding.
没错  大概总结完了
Well, that about sums it up.
我为你感到自豪  迈克尔
I'm proud of you, Michael.
抑制住达成拯救自己协议的诱惑
It's not easy to resist the temptation
那可真不容易
to make a deal that saves yourself.
这个嘛  就我而言
Well, as far as I'm concerned,
我的确达成了拯救自己的协议
I did make a deal that saves myself.
但我来此并不只是为了让你感到自豪
But I didn't just come here to make you proud.
我是来寻求帮助
I came to ask a favor.
尽管说
Name it.
瑞秋和我想在我服刑之前结为夫妻
Rachel and I want to get married before I go.
我知道这通常需要
I know it's not supposed to happen
几个月的时间  但是
for another couple of months but--
但是你没有那个时间
You don't have that kind of time.
我保证不会太麻烦
Look, I promise it's not gonna be too much trouble.
我们不会邀请太多人
We're not gonna invite too many people.
我很荣幸  迈克尔
I'd be honored, Michael.
谢谢你  神父
Thank you, father.
迈克尔  既然你们不打算邀请很多人
Michael, since you're not inviting many people,
我们没必要在这里举行
we don't have to do it in here.
我们总是能在小礼堂举行
We could always do it in the small chapel.
我很感激  神父
I appreciate that, father,
但是我妈妈和爸爸不是在小礼堂举行婚礼的
But my mom and dad weren't married in the small chapel.
很好  你在这儿
Okay, you're here.
是什么如此重要
What's so important I had to
让我为了见你还必须重新安排传讯
reschedule an arraignment to meet with you?
因为那个传讯不能让你
Because that arraignment wasn't gonna lead to you
将一群集团谋杀犯绳之以法
putting corporate murderers behind bars.
让我猜猜
Let me guess.
你掌握了一些犯罪文件
You got a hold of some incriminating documents,
而且你想让我提起公诉
and you want me to prosecute these people
换取免去迈克・罗斯的牢狱之灾
in exchange for keeping Mike Ross out of jail.
谋杀罪换取欺诈罪  简单点
Murder for fraud, straight up.
不感兴趣
Not interested.
听我说
Listen to me.
与之相比  迈克・罗斯犯的罪
Compared to this, what Mike Ross did
几乎就和路边吐痰一样轻微
barely constitutes spitting on a sidewalk.
我知道
I know that.
那你到底是怎么回事
Then what the hell is wrong with you?
告诉你是怎么回事
I'll tell you what's wrong with me.
你
You.
自从你出生那天起
You've been bending the rules
你就一直在破坏规则
since the day you were born,
而我不会再让你得逞
and I'm not letting you get away with it anymore.
你是在和我说笑吗
Are you kidding me?
你把这整个案子的规则都破坏了
You bent rules up and down this entire case.
但我和你之间的区别是
Except the difference between you and me is,
我破坏规则是为了获得正义
I'm bending them to get justice.
将这些人绳之以法就是正义
Putting these people away is justice.
那就直接把他们交给我
Then give them to me anyway.
没错
That's right.
你一直把这个案件作为自己的囊中之物
You've been keeping this case in your back pocket
就是为了以备不时之需
waiting for a rainy day,
因为你就是干那一行的
because that's what you do.
所以或许下一次你有机会
So maybe the next time you have a chance
将杀人犯绳之以法  你应该毫不留情
to put away murderers, you'll do it
而不是留着为了拯救某个毛头小子
instead of saving it up for a chit down the road.
你那么讨厌我吗
You hate me that much?
我不讨厌你  但这就是你做的
I don't hate you, but you did this,
而且你可以想办法逃脱
and you can try to get out of it,
但你不能做的事情  就是否认你做过
but what you can't do anymore is deny you did it.
我没想逃脱此事
I'm not trying to get out of this.
我会代他接受处罚
I'd take the punishment for him.
你曾有大把的机会可以那样做
You had plenty of chances to do that,
但你等到来不及的时候才那样做
but you waited until it was too late.
现在  你想让迈克免受牢狱之灾吗
Now, you want to keep Mike out of prison?
你必须说服他  同意你代他受罚
You have to convince him to let you take his place.
你来这里干什么
What are you doing here?
哈维  我想和你谈谈
Harvey, I want to talk to you.
很好  因为我也想和你谈谈
Good, because I want to talk to you.
-我想让你做我的伴郎  -什么
- I want you to be my best man. - What?
瑞秋和我想结婚
Rachel and I want to get married.
你离进监狱都不到一天了
You're less than a day from prison,
但你还想着婚纱和鲜花吗
and you're thinking about dresses and flowers?
-哈维  -你知道吗
- Harvey-- - You know what?
我做你伴郎有一个条件
I'll be your best man on one condition.
-为时已晚  -的确如此
- That ship has sailed. - The hell it has.
我们还可以给吉布斯打电话
We can still call Gibbs.
我不会给吉布斯打电话
I am not calling Gibbs.
你用脑子想想
Get it through your head.
这件事该由我承担
This is on me.
不  你用脑子想想
No, you get it through your head.
我不会让你进监狱
I am not letting you go to prison
因为我犯下的罪责
for a crime that I committed.
我不会让你去坐牢
Well, I'm not letting you go
而你的判决本会是无罪
when you were gonna be found innocent.
你刚说什么
What did you say?
没错  我撒谎了
That's right, I lied.
陪审团的裁定是无罪
The verdict was not guilty.
-不  我不相信你  -那给那个人打电话
- No, I don't believe you. - Then call the goddamn guy.
你究竟为何要骗我
Why the hell would you lie to me?
因为真相会击垮你
Because the truth would have broken you.
除非你现在想击垮我
Oh, except now you want to break me?
因为这是唯一的方法你会让我去做
Because it's the only way you're gonna let me do this.
你认为给瑞秋带上戒指
You think putting a ring on Rachel's finger
就会让这一切烟消云散吗
is gonna make everything go away?
你知道吗  哈维
You know what, Harvey?
你如果想参加我的婚礼  告诉我
You want to come to my wedding, you let me know.
你想进监狱吗
You want to go to prison?
首要规则  永远不要背对着任何人
Rule number one: Never turn your back on anyone.
我知道你要干嘛  但没有用
I know what you're doing, and it's not gonna work.
我不会试图取代你的位置
I'm not trying to take your place anymore.
我想让你做好准备
I'm trying to get you ready
就像格洛丽亚・丹纳要求我那样
like Gloria Danner asked me to.
-哈维  -因为你很弱
- Harvey-- - Because you're weak.
我不弱
I am not weak.
-那好  打我啊  -不
- Yeah, well, hit me. - No.
-打我  -哈维  住手
- Hit me. - Harvey, stop it.
-听着  -不  你听我说
- Listen. - No, you listen to me.
-你认为你不弱吗  -你这样做
- You think you're not weak? - You're only doing this
-只是因为你感到愧疚  -路易・利特
- because you feel guilty, all right? - Louis Litt
-把你夹在腋下  -但是我不会
- got you in a headlock. - But I am not gonna
-就这样打你  -苔丝的丈夫揍了你一顿
-hit you just because... - Tess's husband kicked your ass.
你接受不了这个事实
You can't handle the fact--
洛根・桑德斯勾引瑞秋
Logan Sanders hooked up with Rachel.
-立马住嘴  -你认为他会
- Stop right now. - What do you think he's gonna
怎么样对付她当你进...
do with her the second you get...
这就是你想要的吗  想要我恨你
Is that what you want? That I hate you,
想要我对你这样做吗
and that you made me do this?
我会因为你而失去一切
I'm gonna lose everything because of you!
迈克  拜托
Mike, please.
我们给吉布斯打电话
Let's call Gibbs.
我做不到
I can't.
我做不到  哈维
I can't, Harvey.
做不到
I can't.
干什么呢
What are you doing?
有时候我就是喜欢来看看
Sometimes I like to come and just watch.
看看你的成就吗
See how far you've come?
差不多吧
Oh, something like that.
吉布斯没有接受协议  杰西卡
Gibbs didn't take the deal, Jessica.
对不起  是我错了
I'm sorry, I was wrong.
不  路易  你没错
No, Louis, you were right.
他是家人  我们应该努力的
He's family, and we had to try.
不管剩下谁
And whoever's left,
我们都会更强
we'll be stronger,
即使我们变小了
even if we're smaller.
对不起  迈克
I'm sorry, Mike.
我不该告诉你判决的真相
I shouldn't have told you the truth about the verdict.
我可能从来都不该打你
I probably shouldn't have hit you all those times.
没关系
It's okay.
知道你还有点血性  让我感觉好很多
Makes me feel better knowing you have it in you.
我得走了
I got to go.
我得去求瑞秋嫁给我
I got to ask Rachel to marry me.
你们不是就要结婚了吗
I thought you were already getting married.
还有些事我得先告诉她
There's something I got to tell her first.
你是来幸灾乐祸的吗
You come here to gloat?
今晚不太合适
Because tonight is not the night.
不  罗伯特
No, Robert.
我是来讲和的
I came here to make peace.
你是对的
You were right.
我该来告诉你  我很抱歉我没有
I should have come to you, and I'm sorry I didn't,
而我余生都会为此后悔
and I will regret that for the rest of my life.
但我听说瑞秋明天要结婚
But I understand Rachel is getting married tomorrow,
我要告诉你  如果你不去
and I'm telling you, if you're not there for her,
你余生都会为此而后悔
you will regret it for the rest of yours.
瑞秋
Rachel?
我在卧室
I'm in the bedroom.
别进来
Don't come in.
为什么  怎么了
Why? What's wrong?
不  没事
No, nothing's wrong.
我在试婚纱
I-I have my dress on.
瑞秋  拜托
Rachel, come on, please.
婚礼会有无数的事情
There are about a million things with this wedding
进行得不尽如人愿
that aren't going as planned,
我都能接受
and I'm fine with that,
但我不要让你看到我穿婚纱的样子
But I'm not gonna jinx it by having you
而毁掉婚礼
see me in my dress.
瑞秋  判决的事我说错了
Rachel, I was wrong about the verdict.
哈维对我说了谎
Harvey lied to me.
他们准备判我无罪的
They were gonna find me not guilty.
瑞秋  求你开门
Rachel, please open the door.
你为什么要现在告诉我
Why are you telling me this right now?
因为你是在知道我会被判有罪后
Because you only wanted to get married
才愿意结婚的
after you found out I was guilty,
而我不想让我们共同生活的开始
and I didn't want to start our life out
基于另一个谎言
with another secret.
你是对的
You were right.
我应该对自己有信心
I should have had faith in myself,
但我没有
and I didn't.
如果你不想结婚了
If you don't want to do this now,
我也理解
I understand.
我们可以在我出来之后结婚
We can do it when I get out.
在我想象中  你就在外面
In my mind, you are out,
没人知道
And no one knows what's gonna happen
婚后会发生什么
after they get married.
他们只知道
They just know what's gonna happen
他们结婚那天会发生什么
the day that they do.
而我们结婚的日子就是明天
And the day we're getting married is tomorrow.
我从没见过更漂亮的新娘子
I don't think I've ever seen a more beautiful bride.
那太好了  因为我也没见过
That's good, because I have never seen
更漂亮的伴娘
a more beautiful maid of honor.
我不想打扰你
So I don't want to bother you,
但我就是想进来
but I just wanted to come in and give you a little bit
提前给你个结婚礼物
of an early wedding present.
唐娜  你不用这样的
Donna, you don't have to do that.
你爸爸妈妈来了
Your mom and dad are here.
谢谢你
Thank you.
别谢我  谢杰西卡
Oh, don't thank me. Thank Jessica.
我先去戴项链了
Um...I'm gonna go and put my necklace on
以免我把眼妆哭花
before I make my mascara run.
好  我在外面等你
Okay, I'll just be outside.
不  等等  我希望
No, no, please, I would, um...
我希望你陪着我
I'd rather you stay.
好
Okay.
唐娜  我能跟瑞秋说句话吗
Donna, can I talk to rachel for a second?
迈克  不行
Mike, you can't.
你在婚礼前不能见她
You can't see her before the ceremony.
唐娜  拜托
Donna, please.
唐娜  能不能帮我把...
Okay, Donna, can you just help me put--
迈克  你不能见到我穿婚纱的样子
Mike, you can't see me in my dress.
瑞秋  我们不能结婚
Rachel, we can't do this.
什么
What?
我来的时候看到了你父母
I just walked in and I saw your parents.
他们是不得不来的
They're here because they have to be,
不是因为他们想来
not because they want to be.
迈克
Mike--
不只是你爸爸的表情
It wasn't just the look on your father's face.
还有你妈妈的
It's the look on your mother's.
他们觉得我在夺走你的未来
They think I'm taking away your future.
你就是我的未来
You are my future.
我不是说我不想结婚
I am not saying that I don't want to get married.
我只是说如果有什么事导致
I'm just saying that if for some reason
我成了夺走你梦想的原因
I was responsible for taking away your dream...
你会永远无法原谅你自己
That you'd never be able to live with yourself.
你去读完法学院  好吗
You go finish law school, okay?
通过律师资格考试  成为律师
And you pass the bar, and you become a lawyer,
然后  两年后我出来
And then...in two years when I get out,
如果你还想嫁给我
if you still want to marry me...
我会的
Oh, I will.
我当然会的
Of course I will.
你怎么知道呢
How'd you know?
我就是知道  而且我不可能
I knew, and there's no way
让你独自去
I'm letting you do this alone.
都走了
They're all gone.
联邦监狱
这不是你的错  哈维
It's not your fault, Harvey.
是我自己做的
I made my case.
我说服你雇了我
I convinced you to hire me.
是我做的决定
I was the one that made the call.
没错
You were.
但那不重要
But it doesn't matter.
因为就算我知道结果
'Cause even knowing how it all turned out...
我也还会再来一次
I'd do it again.
我猜我也会
I guess I would too,
因为我觉得再过一百万年
'cause I never thought in a million years
我也不会认识哪个人
I'd meet someone dumb enough
傻到会为我进监狱
to be willing to go to prison for me.
唐娜总是说
I mean, Donna always said
你在找另一个你
you were looking for another you.
我想你找到了
I guess you found one.
我想是该努力地
I guess it's time to get busy living
忙着生  或赶着死了[《肖申克救赎》]
and get busy dying.
说得一点都没错
Well, that's goddamn right.
在里面多加小心  迈克
Watch your back in there, Mike.
我会的
I will.
人人留学【免费办理】
震撼上线，赶快登陆
www.rrliuxue.com
英、澳、日三国免费办理
众多美国大学，快捷录取
人人留学――开启单向收费新时代